# Matthew Incardona

UX/UI Designer | Entrepreneur

# **About Me**

Passionate entrepreneur experienced in visual design and user research. Pulls from 4 years of experience as a web designer to create great user experiences. Works well in both a team setting and in individually managing their own workflow. Currently looking for a Fall/Spring co-op, available starting August 2022.

#### **Email**

mpi7253@rit.edu

#### Cell

631-371-7358

#### Links

matthewincardona.com

linkedin.com/in/matthew-incardona

#### UX/UI

- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- User research
- Market Analysis
- Design systems
- Lean UX
- Web & mobile design

#### Software

- Figma
- · Adobe XD
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Google Suite

#### Front-End Dev.

- HTML5
- · CSS3
- JavaScript
- ReactJS

## Soft Skills

- Motivated
- Self-starter
- Critical thinker
- · Team player

# Experience

## Founder, UX/UI Designer

Second Desk LLC, Stony Brook, NY / March 2021 - Present

- · Lead a cross-functional team in creating a new DAAS startup.
- Speak directly with potential users to learn about their pain points and decide how to best help them.
- Make high-level decisions about company direction based on user feedback and market analysis.
- Currently, intereviewed 72 users from our target market group and collected important user insights to improve our product and pitch deck.
- Build a user flow diagram to map out interactions and product flow.
- Create wireframes of layouts and convert them into high-fidelity, interactive prototypes using Figma.

## Founder, Web Designer

DouxDolci Web Design, Stony Brook, NY / July 2018 - Present

- Work directly with a variety of clients to design, build, and host custom websites using WordPress and Figma.
- Develop a custom web design process that makes clients consistently happy to work with me.
- Use client pain points to shape the direction of a project to ensure it's something that benefits both them and their business.
- Create strong channels of communication between both parties and set up consistent times for feedback.

# **UX & UI Designer, Front-End Developer**

Bubble Meets, San Francisco, CA / May 2021 - August 2021

- Served as a bridge between the design and development teams in a video conferencing software startup.
- Researched competitors and recorded how users felt about different features of their product.
- Conducted usability testing that helped identify potential pain points in our current product design and flow.
- Helped other teams take a user-centered approach to their work, specifically when brainstorming and building new features.

## Education

# **Rochester Institute of Technology**

BS in Human-Centered Computing, GPA: 3.7

Rochester, NY

Transfer student, expected graduation date May 2024